gainapp.com 2019-06-24

# Privacy Policy - Gain | Social Media and Content Collaboration for Agencies

**Last Updated:** May 24, 2018

Big Propeller respects your right to privacy. This Privacy Policy explains who we are, how we collect, share and use Personal Data about you and how you can exercise your privacy rights.

This Privacy Policy applies to all users of Big Propeller, LLC. websites and services, including but not limited to bigpropeller.com, gainapp.com, gain.app, and gain.li.

If you have any questions or concerns about our use of your Personal Data, please contact us at [privacy@gainapp.com](mailto:privacy@gainapp.com).

## What does Big Propeller / Gain do?

Big Propeller is a US-headquartered provider of software and maker of Gain. Gain is a collaboration and content management software platform for marketing teams. For more information about GAIN see the main website at [https://gainapp.com](https://gainapp.com/).

## Definition of Personal Data

"Personal data" means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. An identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.

"Sensitive Personal Data" means any information consisting of racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, genetic data, biometric data, data concerning health or data concerning a natural person's sex life or sexual orientation.

Big Propeller will never knowingly collect or ask for Sensitive Personal Data from you.

## When We Collect Personal Data

We collect information about you when:

  * You provide it directly to us
  * Third parties such as our service providers (e.g. companies with whom we integrate our Service), provide us with Personal Data about you
  * Personal Data about you is automatically collected in connection with your use of our Service

## What Personal Data We Collect

We collect the following Personal Data from you in connection with the Service:

  *  **Contact and User Account Information:** information we collect to contact you and identify you in the system, such as your first and last name, physical address, email address, telephone number, profile picture, password, and mobile device identification.
  *  **Company Information:** information you provide about companies or organizations you work with/for, such as company or brand name, website, logo, and social media accounts.
  *  **Financial Account Information:** information that you provide in connection with your purchase of the Service, including credit card number, credit card expiration date, credit card verification code, bank account number, bank account title, bank name, and routing number.
  *  **Transaction Information:** information related to transactions you conduct on the Service, such as purchases, interactions with customer support, or when you register for a demo or webinar.
  *  **User Content:** to the extent that you choose to input Personal Data as part of such content, images, comments, and other content that you post to or through the Service.
  *  **Data Collected Automatically:** this may include information like your IP address, device or browser type, broad geographic location (e.g. country or city-level location), and information about how your device has interacted with our Service, including the pages/content accessed, mouse movements, and links clicked.

## Cookies and Similar Tracking Technology

We use cookies and similar tracking technology (collectively, “Cookies”) to collect and use Personal Data about you, including to serve interest-based advertising.

  *  **What are cookies?** Cookies are small data files that are placed on your computer or mobile device when you visit a website or use a platform. Cookies are widely used by website owners in order to make their websites work, or to work more efficiently, as well as to provide reporting information.
  *  **First and third-party cookies.** Cookies set by the website owner (in this case, Big Propeller) are called “first party cookies”. Cookies set by parties other than the website owner are called “third party cookies”. Third party cookies enable third party features or functionality to be provided on or through the website (e.g. like interactive content and analytics). The parties that set these third party cookies can recognise your computer both when it visits the website in question and also when it visits certain other websites.
  *  **Why do we use cookies?** We use first party and third party cookies for several reasons. Some cookies are required for technical reasons in order for our Website to operate, and we refer to these as “essential” or “strictly necessary” cookies. Third parties serve cookies through our Website for analytics and other purposes.
  *  **How can I control cookies?** You have the right to decide whether to accept or reject cookies.
    * You can set or amend your web browser controls to accept or refuse first or third-party cookies. If you choose to reject cookies, you may still use our Website though your access to some functionality and areas of our Website may be restricted. As the means by which you can refuse cookies through your web browser controls vary from browser to browser, you should visit your browser’s help menu for more information.
    * In addition, most advertising networks offer you a way to opt out of targeted advertising. If you would like to find out more information, please visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> or [http://www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/).

## How We Use Personal Data

We use this Personal Data for the following purposes:

  * Operate and improve the Service
  * Provide customer support and assistance
  * Monitor use of the Service to ensure reliability, uptime, security, and fraud prevention
  * Learn more about our users and their behavior in the Service
  * Send you reminders, technical notices, administrative messages, announcements, newsletters, or marketing material through email or other means
  * Evaluate offers, products, or services that may be of interest to users or customers
  * Target offers, products, or services to users or customers

## To Whom We May Disclose Your Information

We may disclose your information, including Personal Data, to the following categories of recipients:

  * To our third party services providers and partners who provide data processing services to us (for example, to facilitate or provide functionality of our Service)
  * To any competent law enforcement body, regulatory, government agency, court or other third party where we believe disclosure is necessary (i) as a matter of applicable law or court order or regulation, (ii) to exercise, establish or defend our legal rights, or (iii) to protect your vital interests or those of any other person
  * To a potential buyer (and its agents and advisers) in connection with any proposed purchase, merger or acquisition of any part of our business, provided that we inform the buyer it must use your Personal Data only for the purposes disclosed in this Privacy Policy
  * To any other person with your consent to the disclosure

We do not share Personal Data with third parties for their own marketing purposes.

Your Personal Data may be transferred to, and processed in, countries other than the country in which you are resident. These countries may have data protection laws that are different to the laws of your country. Specifically, our servers are located in the United States, and our third party service providers operate around the world. This means that when we collect your Personal Data we may process it in any of these countries. However, we have taken appropriate safeguards to ensure that your Personal Data will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## How Long We Retain Personal Data

We retain Personal Data we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements).

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your Personal Data, we will either delete or anonymise it or, in the limited circumstances where this is not possible (for example, because your Personal Data has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your Personal Data and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

## Your Data Protection Rights

We will normally collect Personal Data from you only where we have your consent to do so, where we need the Personal Data to perform a contract with you, or where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms.

The following rights, by law, must be extended to members of the European Union / European Economic Area, in accordance with the GDPR. However, Big Propeller, in its efforts to provide broad data protection to its customers, extends these rights to all users of their Service.

  * You have the right to access, correct, or update your Personal Data at any time.
  * You have the right to withdraw consent to us processing your Personal Data at any time.
  * You have the right to request a full copy of all your Personal Data we have collected at any time.
  * You have the right to request us to delete all your Personal Data we have collected at any time.
  * You have the right to request that we port your personal data in a machine readable format to a new provider if you meet the qualifications set forth in Article 20, Recital 68 of the GDPR.
  * You have the right to object to the use of Personal data for direct marketing purposes, use of personal data based on certain public interests or exercise of official authority, and use of Personal data for research and statistical purposes.

To initiate any of the above requests, please contact us at [privacy@gainapp.com](mailto:privacy@gainapp.com), with attention to Rafael Torres, Big Propeller, LLC’s data protection controller. We will acknowledge and complete your request within 30 days. Note that some of these requests may prohibit your continued use of the Service. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal.

  * You have the right to opt-out of marketing communications we send you at any time. You can exercise this right by clicking on the "unsubscribe" or "opt-out" link in the marketing emails we send you, or by turning off this option in the settings area of the Service.
  * You have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your Personal Data. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority.
  * You have a right to be notified of any serious breaches to your Personal Data no later than 72 hours after Big propeller becoming aware of such breach.

## Minimum Age

We will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 16 without requiring parental consent. Any person who provides their Personal Data to us through our Service represents that they 16 years of age or older.

## Updates to this Privacy Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time in response to changing legal, technical or business developments. When we update our Privacy Policy, we will take appropriate measures to inform you, consistent with the significance of the changes we make. We will obtain your consent to any material Privacy Policy changes if and where this is required by applicable data protection laws.

You can see when this Privacy Policy was last updated by checking the "last updated" date displayed at the top of this Privacy Policy.

## How to Contact Us

If you have any questions or concerns about our use of your Personal Data, please contact us at [privacy@gainapp.com](mailto:privacy@gainapp.com).
